Teiko Middle School
（さつき）ねえねえ 大(だい)ちゃん！
部活何にするか決めた？
Dai-chan, have you decided
which club you're joining?
Huh?
（青峰(あおみね)）あー？ んな
分かりきったこと聞くなよ 今さら
Don't ask the obvious.
I'm joining the basketball team.
バスケに決まってんだろ
This school's supposed to be pretty strong.
ここ相当強いらしいし 楽しみだぜ
I'm excited to play.
Really?
（さつき）へー じゃーアタシ
マネージャーとかやろっかなー？
Maybe I'll be the manager, then.
Want me to pack lunches for you?
お弁当とか作ってあげよっか？
No way.
（青峰）いいわ
（さつき）ん？
（青峰）そんなことしたら
オレ試合出れねーじゃん
I wouldn't be able to play if you did.
（さつき）
ちょっと！ それどういうイミ？
What does that mean?
（黒子(くろこ)）すみません
Sorry.
My bad.
（青峰）ワリ… ってあれ？
Wait, what?
What's wrong?
（さつき）どしたの？
I just...
（青峰）いや…
Never mind.
ま いっか
Hey, do you like books?
（文芸部員）あ！ 君
本が好きなの？ 文芸部とかどう？
Why not join the literary club?
Actually, this is a phone book.
（緑間(みどりま)）
いいや これは電話帳なのだよ
電話帳も立派な本… え？
Phone books are books, too.
なんで 君
電話帳 持ち歩いてるの!?
Why are you walking around with a phone book?
It's Oha-Asa's lucky item.
（緑間）ラッキーアイテムなのだよ
おは朝の
Say, you're huge!
（バレー部員１）
うっわ 君でっかいねー！
Amazing!
（バレー部員２）スゲー！
バレー部！ ぜひバレー部に！
You should join the volleyball team!
（紫原(むらさきばら)）え〜 どーしよーかなー…
I don't know...
Sounds like a pain in the butt.
てか メンドクサイ…
（女子生徒１）ちょっと あの人
すごくかっこよくない？
Isn't that guy really hot?
He's so cool!
（女子生徒２）
ホントだー かっこい〜
Please join our club!
（女子生徒たち）
ぜひお願いしま〜す！
（黄瀬(きせ)）え… あ いやあ…
Actually, I...
Are you sure here is fine?
（運転手）
本当に ここでよろしいのですか？
（赤司(あかし)）
ああ 明日からは送迎もいらない
Yes.
You don't need to drive me to
and from school anymore, either.
それでは… お父上に…
I'll let your father know.
（赤司）父は関係ない
It's not my father's business.
それに 毎朝これでは
笑われてしまうよ
Besides, they'll mock me if I
show up like this every morning.
（赤司）学校くらい
オレの自由にさせてくれ
At least let me do as I please at school.
Did you already join a club?
I'm on the basketball team, of course!
Let's work hard to get into games
so we can play against each other!
I'm joining the basketball club, too.
（黒子）
ボクも… もちろんバスケ部です
Blue Sky
（真田(さなだ)）
まず クラス分けテストを行う
First we'll test you to
divide you into classes.
公式戦にレギュラーとして
出られるのは １軍からだ
Only the first string will play
in official games as regulars.
（１年生１）そもそも—
I heard no one is placed into the
first string out of this test.
このテストで１軍入ったヤツなんて
いないらしーぜ…
（１年生２）
マジで？ よくても２軍ってこと？
Seriously?
So we'll be second string at best?
だったら このテスト
まず目標は２軍入り
I guess we'll aim for second string, then.
（１年生１）がんばろーぜ
Good luck.
（黄瀬）お？ なーんか
盛り上がってるっスねー
They're excited about something.
What club are they?
何部だろ？
どーすっかなー…
What should I do?
There's probably nothing I can't do.
どーせやったらできちゃうからなー
たぶんどれも…
（１年生たち）ハア… ハア…
（３軍コーチ）
テスト結果を発表する
I will now announce the results!
We'll start with the third string.
（真田）まず３軍から
If your name is called, go stand
in front of the third string coach.
名前を呼ばれた者は
３軍コーチの前に行くように
（真田）２番 斉藤(さいとう)信雄(のぶお)
（斉藤）はい！
No. 2, Saito Nobuo.
Yes, sir!
（真田）４番 ナカザワカズヒト
（ナカザワ）はい！
No. 4, Nakazawa Katsuhito.
Yes, sir!
10番 フジタヒロミチ
No. 10, Fujita Hiromichi.
No. 12, Takagiku Yuji.
12番 タカギクユウジ
28番 島田俊助(しまだしゅんすけ)
...Shimida Shunsuke.
No. 30, Tanaka Jun.
30番 田中(たなか) 潤(じゅん)
No. 31, Kuroko Tetsuya.
（真田）31番 黒子テツヤ
（黒子）あ…
That's all.
（真田）以上だ
つづいて ２軍を発表する
Next I'll announce the second string.
（１年生３）よしっ オレ２軍だ！
（１年生４）やったな！
Yes!
I'm in the second string!
All right!
（真田）14番 クロキダイ
No. 14, Kuroki Dai.
35番 ヤギマサオ
No. 35, Yagi Masao.
（真田）続いて １軍を発表する
（黒子）は…
Next I'll announce the first string.
Did he just say first string?
今 １軍って言った？
ウソ… だろ？
You're kidding, right?
No. 8, Aomine Daiki.
（真田）８番 青峰大輝(だいき)
11番 緑間真太郎(しんたろう)
No. 11, Midorima Shintaro.
No. 23, Murasakibara Atsushi.
23番 紫原 敦(あつし)
No. 29, Akashi Seijuro.
29番 赤司征十郎(せいじゅうろう)
That's all.
以上だ
（３軍コーチ）
今回２軍に上がれなかった者は—
Those of you who didn't make
the second string, work harder.
（３軍コーチ）次回 頑張るように
（３軍部員たち）はい！
Yes, sir!
The other day I got my uniform!
I'm still riding the bench during games,
but I'll work harder so I can become a starter!
How are you doing?
Teiko's really strong,
but as long as you work hard,
I know you can succeed.
Faculty Office 2
Stay late to practice?
（３軍コーチ）居残り練習？
それは かまわんが…
下校時間は守るんだぞ
Sure you can, but make
sure you leave on time.
（黒子）はい
Okay.
ハア… ハア… フッ…
ん？ うん… まあ…
Yeah, I guess...
（女子生徒１）
青峰君と幼なじみなんて いいなー
You're so lucky to be
Aomine-kun's childhood friend!
（女子生徒２）
彼女とかいるのかな？
Does he have a girlfriend?
What?
こないだの全中でも大活躍だったし
He carried the last game.
He's so cool!
（女子生徒２人）
カッコいいよねー！ ウフフフッ
Oh!
（女子生徒１）ああっ
（赤司）おっと
（女子生徒１）あ…
Be careful.
気をつけて
いつもありがとう
Thanks for everything.
日々チームを支えてくれて
いることに 感謝している
I appreciate your daily support.
Let's go, Midorima.
行こう 緑間
Akashi-sama's cool, too.
やっぱ赤司様もいいよねー！
（さつき）サマ!?
"Sama"?
だって１年生で
もう副部長だよ!?
He's only a first year,
but he's already the vice captain!
I see...
（緑間）
最近よく考え込んでいるな 赤司
You've been thinking a lot lately, Akashi.
（赤司）ん？ ああ そうだな
Yes, I suppose.
この間の 全中のことか？
Are you thinking about nationals?
We won, but it was close.
優勝こそしたが
危ない場面もあった
Looking ahead to the next two years,
our victory isn't guaranteed.
来年再来年のことを考えると
盤石とは言いがたい
Is it not enough for us to get stronger?
（緑間）オレたちが より実力を
つけるのではダメなのか？
（赤司）戦力的には今でも問題ない
We're already strong enough.
だがすべてが正攻法すぎる
But our methods are too orthodox.
欲しいのは変化…
We need variety.
A sixth man who can change
the flow of the game.
例えば試合の流れを変えたいときに
重宝するシックスマン…
That kind of player.
そんな選手だ
（青峰）うわぁぁぁぁっ！
ナンマンダブ… ナンマンダブ…
ナンマンダブ… ひ〜…
Have mercy, have mercy, have mercy...
Who are you?
（黒子）どちら様ですか？
Huh?
Aomine-kun?
青… 峰君？
（青峰）最近体育館にオバケが
出るって噂があったからよー
I heard rumors about a ghost in the gym.
てっきり出たのかと思ってな
I thought you were him.
I'm just staying late to practice.
（黒子）ただの居残り練習です
（青峰）すげーな
That's amazing.
そこまでやってんのは
１軍でもなかなかいねーよ
Most of the first string
guys don't even do that.
Okay, I know.
（青峰）よっし 決めた！
（黒子）え？
これから毎日ここで
一緒に練習する！
We'll practice together here every day.
そんでいつか
一緒にコートに立とうぜ！
We'll stand on the court together someday.
Are you sure?
（黒子）いいんですか？
（青峰）バーカ
Of course I'm sure.
いいも悪いもあるかよ！
バスケ好きに
悪いヤツはいねーんだよ
Only good guys like basketball.
（３軍コーチ）はっきり言おう
Let me be clear.
オマエにウチの部は無理だ
You're not good enough for our team.
What?
（３軍コーチ）オマエが今まで
頑張ってきていたのは知っている
I know you've practiced hard.
それでも結果 順位が下がった
But your rank has fallen.
I won't make you quit.
（３軍コーチ）退部は命令ではない
決めるのは オマエだ
It's your decision.
う… くうっ…
どうしたら…
ううっ… う…
How...
What? Why?
はあ!?  なんでだよ!?
（黒子）
バスケは好きです… けど—
I like basketball.
But I can't help the team.
ボクはとてもチームの
役に立てそうにありません
（青峰）チームに必要ない
選手なんていねーよ
There's no such thing as
a player we don't need.
たとえ試合に出られなくても—
You may not play in games,
誰よりも遅くまで残って
練習してるヤツが—
but I can't believe someone who stays so
late to practice is completely useless.
まったく無力だなんて話が
あってたまるかよ
I can't guarantee you'll make
it if you don't give up.
諦めなければ
必ずできるとは言わねえ
けど… 諦めたら何も残んねえ
But once you give up, you'll have nothing.
Aomine.
（赤司）青峰
（黒子）あ…
Akashi...
（青峰）赤司
（赤司）最近見ないと思ったら
こんなところにいたのか
I haven't seen you around lately.
This is where you've been?
Yeah.
あー 向こうの体育館は
人が多いから—
The other gym gets crowded.
We always practice here together.
いつも２人で練習してたんだ
Together?
（赤司）２人？
（紫原）
あれー こんな人いたっけ？
Who's this guy?
I'm interested in him.
彼に少し興味がある
（赤司）悪いが…
少しオレにつき合ってくれないか
Sorry, but could you come with me?
I've never met someone
so devoted to basketball
（赤司）初めてだよ
君ほどバスケットボールに
真剣に打ち込み—
その成果が伴ってない人と会うのは
who failed to produce results.
すみません… ちょっと今—
Sorry, but I'm not in any
place to hear those words.
その言葉を受け止められる
精神状態ではないです
すまない！
そういう意味ではないんだ
Sorry. That's not what I meant.
I'm impressed.
（赤司）オレは感心しているんだよ
（黒子）ん…
You're not unathletic.
決して運動神経は悪くない
キャリアと練習量も
充分 経験者と呼べるものだ
Based on your history and practice,
you're an experienced player.
But I feel nothing when I look at you.
にもかかわらず…
君を見て何も感じない
これは きわめて特殊なことだ
This is truly exceptional.
Normally, you can sense an
experienced sports player.
どんな人間でも
何かスポーツをやりこめば—
経験者特有の空気が出る
They can't help it.
出てしまうものなんだ
なのに君は
あまりにも存在感がない
But you're hardly even there.
でもそれは短所ではなく
君の長所だ
However, that isn't your
weakness, it's your strength.
If you can use that,
生かすことができれば
チームにとって必ず—
you will become a powerful
weapon for the team.
大きな武器になる
存在感のなさを生かす…
Use my lack of presence?
そんなことが できるんですか？
Is that possible?
Sorry, but that's all I can say.
（赤司）悪いが…
オレに言えることは ここまでだよ
答えが出たらおいで
Find me when you have your answer.
（緑間）あれが オマエの言う
シックスマンか？
Is he the sixth man you mentioned?
（赤司）聞いていたのか
Were you listening?
You really think he'll change?
（緑間）本気であんなヤツが
化けると思っているのか？
（赤司）さあね
Who knows?
可能性は感じたが
会ったばかりの他人だ
I sensed potential in
him, but he's a stranger.
We're not friends.
友人などではない
あれこれ世話する義理はないね
I'm not obligated to help him.
I simply dangled a thread in front of him.
オレは糸を垂らしただけだよ
それを上ってこられるかどうかは…
彼次第さ
Whether or not he'll climb it
is up to him.
（青峰）チームのために
何ができるか？
What can you do for the team?
赤司とそんな話してたのか
That's what you discussed with Akashi?
Yes.
はい ボクはシュートも
下手だし—
I'm not a good shooter.
あとはパスかアシストかと…
All I can do is pass or assist other players.
ふーん… まあ
赤司だって万能じゃねえし—
Well, Akashi can't do everything.
オマエにしかできないことも
あんじゃね？
There must be something only you can do.
例えば何ですか？
Like what?
Like a pass that curves like crazy.
なんかすげえ曲がるパスとか？
Like, "swoosh"!
ギュワッてよ
Swoosh!
（青峰）ギュワッ！
（黒子）もう いいです
That's enough.
I'm staying here.
それじゃあボクはここで
（青峰）おう また明日なー
Okay. See you tomorrow.
Misdirection
Techniques
（バスケ部員）
おーい 赤司！ お客さんだ
Hey, Akashi!
You have a guest.
３か月ぶりだね 黒子君
Haven't seen you in three months, Kuroko-kun.
Did you find your answer?
（赤司）答えは出たかい？
（黒子）はい
Yes.
（赤司）では さっそくテストを…
（黒子）あの…
Then let's test you immediately.
Um...
If possible, could I show you in a game?
可能ならば… 試合形式で
見てもらえないでしょうか
Nijimura-san.
（赤司）虹村(にじむら)さん
（虹村）あ？
That's him.
（赤司）例の…
（虹村）あぁ？
Oh, right. He's the one you mentioned.
あー あいつかぁ 前言ってたの…
（黒子）フッ！
（選手１）なっ！
シュート！
Shoot!
When did he get there?
（選手２）こいつ いつの間に！
（選手３）どっから わいてきた！
Where'd he come from?
おいおい 何だこりゃ!?
パスもびっくりだが—
What is this?
His passes are surprising,
それより試合中に
姿を見失うとかあんのか？
but how can people lose
sight of him during a game?
（赤司）ミスディレクション
（虹村）あ？
Misdirection.
What?
手品などで使われる
人の視線を誘導するテクニックです
It's a technique used in magic tricks
for directing a person's focus.
手品？
Magic?
For example, before he intercepts a pass,
（赤司）
例えば カットを切る直前—
目線や仕草で マークマンの目を
ボールや他の選手に誘導する
he uses his gaze and movements
to direct his mark's attention
to the ball or another player.
Combined with his natural lack of
presence, he seems to disappear.
結果 もともとの影の薄さと
相まって—
彼はコート上から
幻のように姿を消す
Second String
Third String
こうなることは全部
分かってたんか オマエ？
Did you know this would happen?
（黒子）ハア… ハア…
（赤司）いいえ 期待以上です
No. He exceeded my expectations.
（３軍コーチ）
オマエは今日から１軍に合流だ
Starting today, you're on the first string.
チャンスをものにしたな
You got your chance.
はい！
Yes, sir.
（さつき）すみませーん
黒子君って こっちに来てますか？
Excuse me.
Is there a Kuroko-kun here?
（黒子）あ ボクです
That's me.
He's invisible...
（さつき）うすっ！ 影うすっ！
He's barely there...
I brought Kuroko Tetsuya-kun.
黒子テツヤ君 連れてきました！
Thanks.
おう サンキュー
You're here, Tetsu.
来たな！ テツ
やあ… 待っていたよ
Hey. I've been waiting for you.
Welcome to the first string of the
Teiko Middle School basketball team.
ようこそ 帝光(ていこう)バスケ部１軍へ
100 Battles 100 Victories
そして肝に銘じろ
Remember this.
今この瞬間から
君の使命はただひとつ…
From this moment, you have only one purpose.
勝つことだ
Winning.
（赤司）灰崎(はいざき)です
（虹村）ああん!? よこせ！
It's Haizaki.
What? Give me that!
灰崎！ テメェ今どこだ!?
Haizaki, where are you?
（灰崎）すんませーん
風邪ひいちゃって… ゴホッ！
Sorry, but I've got a cold.
くっ！ ぬううっ…
Haizaki's out with a cold.
灰崎は風邪で欠席です
（真田）黒子
（黒子）あ…
Kuroko.
代わりにオマエがスタメンだ
You'll start instead.
（選手一同）
よろしくお願いします！
Let's have a good game!
Tetsu, relax.
テツ リラックス… う！
うお ダメだ！ 生まれたての
子鹿みてーになってんぞ!?
You're hopeless.
You're like a newborn fawn.
（紫原）でやっ！
落ち着いて 黒子君
まずはゆっくり…
Calm down, Kuroko-kun.
We'll start slow.
Sorry. I tripped on my own feet.
（黒子）すみません
足がもつれてしまって…
I'm okay.
（黒子）大丈夫です
（赤司）いや—
You're not okay at all.
（赤司）全然大丈夫ではないね
（紫原）ありえないんだけど…
（青峰）テツ…
I don't believe this.
Tetsu...
He was subbed out after only a second.
わずか１秒で交代とは…
これはさすがに想定外だ
I wasn't expecting this.
（真田）仕方がない… 虹村
（虹村）はい！
We have no choice.
Nijimura.
Yes, sir.
Teiko, player substitution!
（記録係）
帝光！ メンバーチェンジです！
（他校選手１）出たぞ
帝光キャプテン 虹村修造(しゅうぞう)！
It's Teiko's captain Nijimura Shuzo.
He's the strongest middle
school power forward.
（他校選手２）中学ナンバーワンの
呼び声も高いパワーフォワードだ！
（虹村）
まー 細けー説教は後だ
I'll lecture you later.
First, let's win.
まずは勝つぞ
（虹村）っしゃあ！
（真田）バカモン！
Yes!
Fool!
これは１年のシステムを
確認する試合だと言ったろう！
We're playing to see how the
first-years work together.
You have to hold back.
オマエはもっとセーブして戦え！
（真田）鼻血は止まったか？
（黒子）はい
Has your nose stopped bleeding?
Yes.
（真田）よし… 虹村とチェンジだ
Okay. You'll switch with Nijimura.
（赤司）フッ！
（黒子）えいっ！
Out of bounds!
（審判）アウト･オブ･バウンズ！
黒ボール！
Black ball!
（紫原）んぎっ あのさ〜
何今の… ふざけてんの？
What was that?
Are you messing around?
（黒子）ふざけてません
No, I'm not.
ひねり潰すよ？
I'll crush you.
Please don't do that.
（黒子）ひねり潰さないでください
（緑間）ハア…
I see.
（緑間）なるほどな…
スタイルはだいたい分かった
I understand his style.
確かに面白いが…
It's interesting, but...
He makes too many mistakes.
（赤司）ミスが多すぎる…
Is it nerves?
緊張か まだスタイルが
自分のものに なっていないのか…
Is his style not his own yet?
その両方か
Or is it both?
Minamihara
Teiko
Good Luck
（紫原）峰ちんー 何それ？
Minechin, what's that?
弁当… さつきの…
Satsuki made me lunch.
（青峰）いる？
（紫原）グロいからいい〜
Want some?
No, it looks gross.
（青峰）
ちょっとコンビニ行ってくる
I'm going to the convenience store.
（紫原）あれ〜
これ峰ちんのサイフじゃねえ？
Huh?
Isn't this Minechin's wallet?
Where did he go?
（緑間）何をしに行ったのだよ
あいつは
（紫原）コンビニ〜
The convenience store.
I'll take it to him.
（黒子）ボクが届けてきます
急に投げないでください
Don't just throw things at me.
（紫原）
えー そっちがトロいんでしょ〜
Huh? You're just slow.
（青峰）テツを降格って…
You're demoting Tetsu?
まだ午後の試合が残ってる！
もう一度だけ あいつを…
We still have a game this afternoon.
Can't he play one more game?
No. He's not worth observing anymore.
ダメだ
これ以上は見る価値はない
彼は降格にする
I'm demoting him.
次も
もしダメだったら—
If he fails again, you can demote me, too!
オレも一緒に降格する！
だから—
Put him in one more time!
もう一度 あいつを
使ってやってください！
I know he'll save us someday.
あいつはいつか
オレたちを救ってくれる
なんでか 分かんねーけど
そんな気がするんだ！
I'm not sure why, but I know he will!
Say hi.
（虹村）ほらアイサツ
（灰崎）うぃ〜す
Hey...
（帝光一同）灰崎… 顔ヒデエ！
Haizaki's face looks awful...
２軍のヤツがゲーセンで遊んでる
こいつ見つけてよ
A second string guy found him in an arcade.
He seemed pretty healthy,
so I brought him here.
風邪だってわりに
元気そうだから連れてきた
But he seems nearly dead...
（帝光一同）だがもう虫の息だ…
（真田）午後の
スターティングメンバーは—
Our starting lineup this
afternoon is Akashi, Midorima,
赤司 緑間 紫原 青峰 灰崎だ
Murasakibara, Aomine, and Haizaki.
Kuroko, you'll play in the second half.
黒子は後半から出てもらう
いいな？
Got it?
Haranishi
Teiko
パスの速さを修正する必要がある
You need to fix the speed of your passes.
１軍の動きは速い
First string members are quick.
You need to pass sooner than you would
２軍３軍よりも
一歩早く出さなければ間に合わない
for second or third string players.
You have a timing issue.
要は タイミングの問題だ
それと… 影の薄さを
コントロールできて初めて—
Also, your Misdirection is most powerful
ミスディレクションは
大きな力を発揮する
when you control your lack of presence.
Don't wear your emotions on your sleeve.
そのためには
感情を表に出さないこと
You must have the will to fight.
闘志は必要だ だがそれは秘めろ
But keep it hidden.
（黒子）ハア… フー…
分かりました
I understand.
（緑間）ボールが…
The ball...
（灰崎）曲がった!?
Curved?
（紫原）赤ちんのところから—
Passes keep coming from Akachin
with impossible timing.
来るはずのないタイミングで
ボコボコ パスがある…
ちょーラク
This is super easy.
機能することで
ここまで変わるのか…
Does it make this much of
a difference when it works?
黒子！
（真田）黒子テツヤ
Kuroko Tetsuya, this year you'll
officially join the bench.
今年の試合から
正式にベンチ入りしてもらう
背番号は15
You're No. 15.
シックスマンとしての活躍を
期待する
I expect great things from our new sixth man.
From: Ogiwara Shigehiro
Congratulations!
I knew you could do it.
See you at this summer's nationals!
It's a promise!
Preview
Kuroko's a regular, huh?
（虹村）黒子がレギュラーか
オマエの目は
確かだったってことだな
I guess you weren't wrong.
It's the product of his hard work.
（赤司）黒子自身の
努力の結果ですよ
But you're the one leading the team.
（虹村）でも こっからチームを
引っ張るのはオマエだろ？
（赤司）虹村さん？
Nijimura-san...
...Sorry
I expect great things from you, Akashi.
（虹村）期待してるぜ 赤司